Alle Sava

Web Designer & Frontend Developer sava.io alle@sava.io

Summary

Work & residence status:

EU citizen, without work or residence restrictions within EU/EEA

Name: Alina Sava Preferred name: Alle

Highlights:

- 15 years of experience in both web/UI design and development
- · very strong willingness to learn

Language skills:

English C2 [fluent, full professional proficiency] French B2 [conversational level, good understanding] Spanish B2 [conversational level, good understanding] German B1 [conversational level, medium understanding] Italian A2 [basic conversational level, medium understanding]

Swedish A1 [very basic conversation, basic understanding]

Technical Skills

Development:

Token-based design systems

HTML5

CSS3

SASS/SCSS

Git, GitHub, GitLab

Cross-browser Compatibility

WordPress theme development

JavaScript

Performance optimisation with Lighthouse and Performance Insights Variable fonts and web typography

On-page SEO and schema.org JSON-LD / structured data markup

React, plus some familiarity with Angular and Typescript

Some experience with jQuery, REST APIs, PHP (due to WordPress)

Static site generators and other theme development (CecilApp, Gatsby)

IntelliJ suite (PHPStorm, WebStorm)

Familiar with Agile Development (Scrum), Jira

Design:

Adobe Illustrator (since 2016)

Adobe Photoshop (since 2007)

Adobe XD (since 2019)

Limited experience with: Sketch (2017-2018 version), Figma

Design approach: token-based design systems with a strong focus on project needs and guidelines, usability, typography, and user experience.

Various limited experience with other software and coding skills I experimented with.

Web Designer & Frontend Developer

Work Experience

06.2015 - present

Web Designer & Frontend Developer

Commissioned work:

- altafino.com [full project]
- cowork.to [logo design] viewable on next CV page
- EcovillageList.com [logo and web design, frontend development] I was part of a 4 person team that built this nonprofit project with which we participated in the 2019 Climate Change Fixathon challenge

Name: Alina Sava Preferred name: Alle

I initiated, fully designed, developed, and later sold multiple projects:

- FontsArena.com [acquired 2022]
- BrutalistThemes.com [acquired 2022]
- glam.ink [acquired 2018]
- FreebiesCafe.com [acquired 2017]
- WPCrumbs.com [acquired 2017]
- CraftedPixels.net [acquired 2016]

For all projects my work included logo design, web design, development, research and writing, on-page SEO, commercial products design and development, sometimes SSG theme development, custom fonts and icons.

As hobby I created:

- 2 custom fonts, using FontSelf (Illustrator plugin).
 - Sysfont a revival of Susan Kare's original Chicago, the default typeface in Apple's System (80s operating system, MacOS's precursor)
 - W95FA a modern scalable re-creation of the raster default Windows 95 font (MS Sans Serif)

Both fonts will soon have a proper website at sysfont.com (currently it redirects to FontsArena.com page).

- a CSS framework based on css grid, and made it publicly available as a npm package. GitHub repo at https://github.com/allesava/gridkit

06.2013 - 06.2015

Web Designer [HTML5, CSS3, WordPress, Bootstrap, jQuery, Modernizr]

07.2011 - 03.2013

Web Designer @ TreeWorks

I worked on VacationHomeRentals.com [acquired by TripAdvisor], HawaiiJobEngine.com, GroupTripOrganizer.com, zelist.ro, tpu.ro, gustos.ro, ubernuts.ro, tecnos.ro, cristiroman.ro

02.2009 - 07.2011

Web Designer @ WebDesignAgency.ro

My work included designing in Photoshop, slicing, coding it in html&css and implementing it on 2 custom in-house ecommerce platforms.

I designed GSMnet.ro, the shop that won the first prize for "Best Online Merchant Award for the Telecommunications Category" and second prize in the "Traditional Online Shops Category" at the 2009 GPeC Gala. (as of 2014 the website was redesigned)

Alle Sava

Web Designer & Frontend Developer

Education

Bachelor's Degree Automotive Engineering Ovidius University

Name: Alina Sava Preferred name: Alle

Logo Portfolio

altafino



visual Coffee







freebies cafe

wp crumbs